He's admitting that we used to be on
opposite sides, but now we're on the
same side. When did al-Qaeda stop being
head choppers?
>> Well, that's that's a good question. And
there's never been any explanation by
the US government as to why and even
when the policy changed.
>> Our guest is here. Uh John Kuryako is a
former CIA analyst, case officer, senior
investigator for the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee, and former
counterterrorism consultant. He was the
first to reveal that the CIA
waterboarded detainees and to label
waterboarding as torture. He
subsequently became the sole CIA agent
to go to jail in connection with the US
torture program. Of course, of course,
the person who goes to jail is the
person who except that he was uh
prosecuted by the Obama administration
under the Espionage Act for being a
whistleblower whereas none of the
individuals who actually engaged in the
actual torture were prosecuted. Welcome
back to the show. John Kuryako. Good to
see you in person.
>> Thank you. Good to see you.
>> John, I wanted to show you get your
reaction to this. Now, you know this.
This is the US amb embassy in Syria
tweeted this out. We remain committed to
bringing leading AQS figures in HTS to
justice, meaning al-Qaeda. That's
basically al-Qaeda.
>> I know where he is. John, can you pass
it along? You get my money?
>> Yeah. I think he's uh sitting with David
Petraeus uh in New York.
>> Well, so here here he is. Here he is
with our Secretary of State. So, they
want they had a $10 million reward on
him and now here he is. And uh uh oh,
look out. Here comes a lady showing her
legs. That's against your he might have
to kill her. Anyway, uh so there he is.
>> Called for forgiveness, Jimmy.
>> So this literally this guy, he takes off
the uh uh terrorism garb, shaves his
beard, and puts on a Brooks Brother
suit, and now he's meeting with the
Secretary of State in the United States.
This is al-Qaeda leader in Syria. And
here he is meeting with the former uh
general and head of the CIA, former head
of the CIA. And this is what the CIA had
said.
>> We're nationalist certainly. Yes, a
degree of political Islam.
Uh but but frankly, what you have done
uh since toppling the Balad regime has
validated what it is that I assessed it
and I was criticized by the way quite
considerably.
I just want you to tell you really on
behalf of all the people who are here uh
that this conversation has truly filled
me with enormous hope. Uh it has been
very very heartening and illuminating.
Um your vision is is powerful and clear.
Uh your demeanor itself is is very
impressive as well. And so again on
behalf of all here and all those that
are watching virtually and so forth, we
thank you for sharing your vision today.
We wish you strength and wisdom in the
difficult work ahead. We obviously hope
for your success inshallah because at
the end of the day your success is our
success. Thank you very much.
>> So that that's he's talking to the head.
Now that's the head. Now, I know people
who joined the military to go fight that
guy, to go kill that guy because they
attacked us on 911.
>> And now here is
>> question Jimmy.
>> What's that?
>> Uh, John is there. So, I've been told a
bunch of times, but I don't know if it's
true. It sounds so I mean, this is
already crazy, but was that guy in the
Daniel Pearl video standing behind
Daniel Pearl? That's what they they say
about him. You know, a talking a lot of
work went into into figuring out who was
in the room in that Daniel Pearl video.
Just as as background, I saw Daniel
Pearl the day he died.
>> Oh, no kidding.
>> I happened to be uh working in the
American embassy in in Islamabad,
Pakistan. Um I had a friend uh Tommy
McCale who was a Port Authority of New
York, New Jersey detective on loan to
the FBI in Islamabad. We hit it off and
he calls me one day and he said, "Hey,
there's a Wall Street Journal uh
reporter down here, Daniel Pearl. Uh he
wants to uh to check in because he's
going to go to a meeting later that's a
high threat meeting." I said, "Yeah,
I'll talk to him." So, we went
downstairs. I went downstairs. Tommy was
already downstairs. We met with Daniel
Pearl. And uh I said, "So, who you going
to meet with?" And he said, "Oh, it was
I forget, Ji Muhammad or Ansar Allah. I
forget. It was one of these groups." And
I said, I remember looking at Tommy and
saying, "That is a very bad idea." And
he said, "No, I've been working on this
for 6 months. We've been dialoguing for
6 months. They finally agreed to see
me." I said, "I don't think you
appreciate just how dangerous it is
here." And he said, "No, I'm doing it.
I'm doing it." And then they found his
head on one side of town, they found his
torso on the other side of town.
What did you think was going to happen?
But anyway,
the Pakistanis arrested someone who who
confessed to being the guy to actually
saw Daniel Pearl's head off. But then
after waterboarding Khalich Shake
Muhammad 187 times, he confessed to
killing Daniel Pearl and sawing his head
off. In fact, it was KSM who said, "If
you look at the video, you see how hairy
the arm is. Look at my arm. How hairy it
is." It's like, "Yeah, you have a hairy
arm, but there's already a guy that's
been sentenced to a thousand years in
prison for confessing to the Daniel
Pearl killing." Sure, it could have been
this guy. Golani, we have no idea. We
don't know if we can trust the
Pakistanis. Did they just arrest this
guy because he was a pain in their ass
and they knew that the Americans would
be happy that somebody was arrested? I
think that was probably the case. This
guy, Golani, don't forget, not only was
a senior member of al-Qaeda, he was the
deputy founder of ISIS. Why? Because
al-Qaeda wasn't radical enough.
And then all of a sudden, no, no, no.
We're all best friends.
>> Now we're best friends. It's so
>> best friends. if you got your dick blown
off at war and then saw I mean
>> people in the intel community
>> this is my question dude did you
anticipate seeing something like this
cuz this
>> never
so at so what first got me on the bad
algorithm on YouTube was that I was
debunking the the CIA narrative or the
establishment state department narrative
about the Syrian war. Yes. And I was
showing that these gas attacks
>> easy to attack.
>> And and so um I was telling people that
just like Tulsi was if you get rid of
Assad, who's going to take over? It's
going to be al-Nusra, al-Qaeda, ISIS.
That's who's going to take over the
country. You guys realize this. And
people called me a conspiracy theorist.
I still, if you Google me, it's still
I'm a conspiracy theorist about Syria,
even though everything I said came true.
>> No, I I'm with you 100% on Syria. I said
on my own radio show, which of course
has been cancelled thanks to sanctions
by the Biden administration, I said
whether you like his politics or not,
>> Bashar al-Assad is the only thing
standing between the Christian community
in Syria and complete annihilation. The
Washington Post then had somebody
listening to the show and they said that
I was a threat to our democracy
because I was raising these issues.
>> Yeah. No, your kne your threats to the
military-industrial complex and uh
>> Sasha Baron would have thrown you out of
the room for that kind of talk.
>> That's right. You remember that? Last
time I was on, we talked about that.
>> So, let me
>> talk about Yeah. Sorry.
>> Let me just play Let me play one more.
>> Please join again in welcoming President
Ahmed al-Shara to the stage. As you
know, Mr. President, I spent over 37
years in the US Army. Uh, and I was a
soldier, not a diplomat. So, I hope
you'll forgive me if I speak with the
directness of the old soldier that I am
as I get the first question out of the
way because the fact is that we were on
different sides uh when I was commanding
the surge in Iraq.
>> Yeah. He was on the side of the guys who
blew up the Twin Towers according to
you. So now we're friends with them. So
now it So now we're supposed to So why
do we still have the emer uh the um uh
the authorization for the use of
military force? uh given to the
president to go fight this guy if this
guy's now our friend.
>> Why are they trying to reboot ISIS?
Can't we have our best friend in Syria
call up ISIS and tell him to knock it
off? Seriously.
>> So my so my theory is and I want to run
it past you is that uh and I've thought
this for a long time is that ISIS and
al-Qaeda well al-Qaeda was obviously an
invention of the United States in some
way. Hillary Clinton even talked about
that how we created
>> ISIS was as well
>> and ISIS I think is just they the the
key is they never attack Israel. So ISIS
u there when there someone gets injured
Israeli doctors take care of ISIS and
they say it's because of God or
something most moral army in the world
>> and they never attack and they they
never attack inside Israel. Isn't that
wild? So that's I'm a thousand% sure
that the United States and the Mossad
invented ISIS and al-Qaeda. And the
reason why is that we can now use them
as an excuse to go bomb and overturn any
country we want after the after 9/11. We
can because the the AUMF, the
authorization for the use of military
force. So you don't have to declare war.
The president can just unilaterally,
which is what we've been doing in Syria
and Libya and what we did in uh uh Yemen
and we just doing it all over the place.
>> Somalia.
>> Somalia. Um, and the second one is, uh,
so we get to use them as a, uh, as an
excuse to go do that. And, uh, now I
forget what the second one is. God damn
it. But, um, here it is. Uh, he's
admitting that we used to be on opposite
sides, but, now we're on the same side.
When did al-Qaeda stop being head
choppers? Well, that's that's a good
question and there's never been any
explanation by the US government as to
why and even when the policy changed.
You know, Donald Trump just said
apparently spontaneously one day, "We're
lifting sanctions on Syria."
Why? You just saved a guy who co-founded
ISIS, a guy who was the head of
al-Qaeda, then called the Nuslar front
in uh in Syria. Why? What? What
necessitated this change in policy? This
is the guy that dedicated his life to
murdering Americans. Yes. What do you
tell all the military people or or the
families of military people who were
killed in this fight?
>> Oh, I know for nothing. I know
>> ICE remember ICT wrote Cop Killer and it
was really controversial, but later he
became a beloved law and order cop on
TV.
>> That's a good That's a good point.
They're all actors. It's all fake.
Yeah.
>> So, yeah. So, they Oh, so the second
reason is they invented ISIS and
al-Qaeda to do their dirty work like in
our dirty war in Syria. So, we funded
the CIA funded uh al-Qaeda and ISIS and
al-Nusra and often and then the Pentagon
would would fund other groups of
terrorists inside. I saw Rambo three
>> to get rid to get rid of Assad. And and
a lot of times or or sometimes often
enough that it got reported in the
Washington Post that the CIA backed
terrorists would be fighting the
Pentagon backed terrorists and they
would fight each other. So that happened
that's not on the front page obviously
that's on page 78 right
>> of the Washington Post but it's there.
>> I wonder if they do that here too.
>> I wonder if they do that here. Yeah, of
course they do. What if they're
radicalizing furries here?
>> Just to show you how how ridiculous this
is this kind of overall policy. One of
the things that I did when I was
stationed in Pakistan, one of the things
that everybody does when they're
stationed in Pakistan is there's a
reward program out there for Stinger
missiles. Starting in 1986, we provided
Stinger missiles to Mujahedin in
Afghanistan to fire at Soviet aircraft,
mostly um helicopters. It changed the
course of the war. The Russians, the
Soviets ended up pulling out. But there
are hundreds of Stinger missiles still
out there. their shoulder fired,
>> right?
>> So, we've got this rewards program where
if you bring a Stinger missile into the
embassy, uh, we'll give you 100 grand in
cash. So, every once in a while, I'd get
a call from the front gate. Um, there's
a guy here. He's got a missile in the in
the bed of his pickup truck and, uh, he
says it's a stinger. So, I come out and
I look at the missile and they all have
these little these little plaques on
them with serial number. So, I I tell
the guy, "Hold on. Have a cup of coffee.
I'm gonna make a call and I'll get back
to you." So, I put it in a quick cable.
I send it to headquarters. This is the
number. They say, "Yep, it's one of
ours." I go to the money room. I pull
out a hundred grand. I go down front.
Here's your money. I take my missile and
that's one more off the street. Now, was
that really a smart thing to do to just
turn over Stinger missiles to the
Mujahedin knowing that they have a shelf
life of a good 40 years? And they can be
used against us.
>> Yeah. No, that was not a good idea.
>> They don't go bad. The
>> No,
>> they don't. It's like the MREs.
>> Totally. Seriously,
>> we're still eating MREs that have
manufactured dates from the Vietnam War.
>> Well,
>> and they're still just as delicious.
>> Listen, the ham and eggs, you can't go
wrong.
>> Come see me on tour. I'll be in
Sacramento, San Francisco, Irvine,
California, Sydney, Melbourne, and
Brisbane, Australia, and then Burbank,
California, the day after Thanksgiving.
Go to jimmydor.com for a link for
tickets.
[Music]